(日向翔陽･ﾅﾚｰｼｮﾝ)＜目の前に
立ちはだかる高い高い壁＞
A massive, massive wall stands
in front of me, blocking my way.
＜その向こうは
どんな眺めだろうか＞
I wonder what the view is like on the other side.
＜どんなふうに
見えるのだろうか＞
What does it look like?
＜頂の景色＞
The view from the summit—
＜俺独りでは
決して見ることのできない景色＞
it's something I'll never be able to see alone.
＜でも独りではないのなら＞
But if I'm not alone...
(一同)お願いします
Let's have a good match!
Episode One:
The End and The Beginning
≪よしゃ
Yes!
あ
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ](観客たち)わあ
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ](ｱﾅｳﾝｻｰ)決また
まさに小さな巨人
He nailed it!
He's the Little Giant!
これで５連続ポイントです
春の高校バレ全国大会
That's makes five points in a row!
This is the Spring High School
National Volleyball Tournament.
１９０センチ近い選手の
ひしめく中
烏野高校の小さな巨人が
所狭しと飛び回ています
Crowed by players nearly 190 cm tall, the Little Giant of Karasuno High jumps around strutting his stuff!
Karasuno, from the next town over?
烏野て隣町のあそこか
大したもんだなぁ
That's impressive.
(泉)翔ちゃん早く
グラウンド取られる
Shou, hurry. We'll lose our spot!
烏野
Karasuno...
Approximately 3 years and 3 months later
(泉)翔ちゃん待てよ
Shou, wait up!
It's huge.
エアサロンパスのにおい
It smells like Air Salonpas!
(泉)翔ちゃんちょと
緊張しすぎじゃない
Shou, you need to loosen up.
(関向)お上りさんかよ
だだて
What are you, a hick?
B-But this is my first real match.
ちゃんとした大会初めてだから
Finally, for the first time in three years.
３年目にしてやと
(関向)ほんと
よく出場までこぎ着けたなぁ
I'm amazed you got us a spot.
イズミンもコジも
Izumin, Kouji,
助人に来てくれてありがとう
(関向)やめろ
thanks for coming to help out our club.
Stop that!
(泉)俺たちひと足先に
大会終わちゃたしね
Our tournament already wrapped up.
And thank you, first-years!
１年生もありがとう
It's a miracle that the three of you joined the team!
３人も
入てくれたなんて奇跡だよ
(森)あはい
まだ素人同然ですけど
Oh, yes.
We're still total amateurs, though.
(関向)泣くなよ翔陽
な泣いてない
Don't cry, Shouyou!
I'm not crying!
(泉)超涙目だよ
(鈴木)ああの日向先輩
You're practically a waterfall.
U-Um, Hinata, we really should get warmed up.
早くアプ取た方が
(泉)ほらキャプテン仕切て
Come on, Captain. Take charge!
(関向)そうだよ
俺たち急に引張られてきて
Yeah!
You dragged us into this, and we still don't know the rules!
ルｰルもよく分かんないんだから
わ分かてるよ
I-I know that.
やと出られた大会
出るからには勝つぞ
We barely made it into this tournament.
We're in it to win it!
Miyagi Prefecture Boys' National Junior High Volleyball Tournament Qualifier Bracket
(泉)えこの
即席素人チムで勝つつもり
Miyagi Prefecture Boys' National Junior High Volleyball Tournament Qualifier Bracket
What?!
You're gonna put in our ramshackle amateur team to win?
Miyagi Prefecture Boys' National Junior High Volleyball Tournament Qualifier Bracket
当たり前だろ
(関向)相手の北川第一て
Of course!
Miyagi Prefecture Boys' National Junior High Volleyball Tournament Qualifier Bracket
What's our opponent Kitagawa First like?
どうなの
分かんない
Miyagi Prefecture Boys' National Junior High Volleyball Tournament Qualifier Bracket
I dunno,
but I'm gonna beat 'em!
けどやてみせる
(泉)はは
(２人)あ
んいい
(泉)あすいませんほら
うわ
Uh, excuse us!
C'mon.
They're huge.
(応援団)わあ
なんだ
What the...
コンコンコンコン
(応援団)北一北一
Certain
Victory
Kitagawa First Junior High School
Kita First!
北川第一だ
でけ
It's Kitagawa First.
They're huge.
They're really intimidating.
威圧感ハンパねぇ
優勝候補だろ
They're the favorites, right?
王様がいんだろ
何それ
The have the King.
What?
Didn't you know?
(選手)知らねぇの影山飛雄
コト上の王様て言われてる
They call Kageyama Tobio the King of the Court. He's supposed to be an incredible setter.
すげぇセタなんだて
(関向)ちょあいつらが相手
Wait. We're playing against those guys?!
王様てなんだよ
大丈夫だて
What's this king crap?!
It's fine!
相手がどんなにノポでも
打ち抜いてみせる
I'll blast through 'em no matter how gangly they are!
(泉)確かに翔ちゃんのジャンプ
すごいもんな
Yeah, 'cause you can really jump, Shou.
We're counting on you!
その前に便所
I need to use the can first.
(部員)なあ雪ヶ丘中て
聞いたことないんだけど
I've never heard of Yukigaoka Junior High. Have you?
つうか人数少なくなかた
リベロもいねぇの
They don't have enough players.
They don't even have a libero!
They're they size of grade school kids.
背もほぼ小学生じゃん
試合になんないしょ
It's no competition at all.
おいお前ら
(３人)え
Hey, you guys!
あんまりなめるなよ
ギュルギュル
I wouldn't push my luck, if I were you.
く俺の腹が治りしだい
As soon as my stomach feels better, I'm gonna
whomp you on the court, so prepare yourselves.
試合で痛い目見してやるから
覚悟しとけよ
ギュルギュル
うぅぐ
マジすか期待してます
ほら小学生
For real?
I'm looking forward to it!
He's a grade schooler.
(部員)バカ
キャプテンマク付いてんじゃん
Idiot! He's got the captain's mark.
≪バカにしやがて
They're mocking me!
Hey, second-years!
(影山飛雄)おい２年
公式ウォムアプ始まるぞ
早くしろ
The official warmup is starting.
Get moving.
Sorry. I'll be right there!
すいませんすぐやります
やべ影山先輩だ
Shit. It's Kageyama.
(部員)ほら急げ
ドリンクあと２本
Get moving! We need two more drinks!
(部員)そんなたくさん作ても
飲まねぇだろ相手あれだぞ
We'll never drink all those anyway.
Look at who we're up against.
な
(部員)はは確かに
You're right.
なんだと
お前ら
Say what?!
Hey, you guys.
ベンチにも入れないくせに
対戦相手見下せるほど
You aren't even warming the bench yet.
Do you think you're tough enough to disrespect our opponent?
強いつもりなのか
(３人)い
学校の名前に乗かてんじゃねぇよ
Don't act like you own our school name.
S-Sorry!
すすいません
≪怖ぇ
Scary...
お俺も今ビシと
言てやるところだたんだけどね
Y-You caught me just as I was about to tell them off myself!
ギュルギュル
う
Someone who can't even keep themselves healthy shouldn't act so high and mighty.
体調管理もできてないヤツが
偉そうなこと言うな
だからなめられるんだろ
なんだと
That's why they look down on you.
Excuse me?
What did you come here for?
一体何しにここへ来たんだ
思い出づくりとかか
To make a memory?
勝ちに来たに決まてる
I came here to win, of course!
随分簡単に言うじゃねぇか
You make it sound easy.
確かに俺はでかくないけど
I may not be that tall,
but...
俺はとべる
I can jump!
負けが決まてる勝負なんかない
諦めさえしなきゃ
No match is a guaranteed loss, as long as we don't give up!
Not giving up isn't as easy as it sounds!
諦めないて
口で言うほど簡単じゃねぇよ
やと
やとちゃんとコトで
I'm finally...
I'm finally making it on the court to play volleyball with six teammates.
６人でバレができるんだ
I'll win the first round, then the second round...
１回戦も２回戦も
勝て勝て
I'll keep winning and winning!
いぱい試合するんだ俺たちは
We're going to give it our all!
１回戦も２回戦も
In the first round, the second round,
決勝も全国も
the final, nationals...
勝てコトに立つのは
この俺だ
I'll be the one still standing on the court at the end!
翔ちゃん
あイズミン
Shou.
Izumi.
(泉)何怖そうな人怒らしてんの
トイレに行たんじゃないの
Why are you making that scary guy angry?
I thought you went to the bathroom.
早く戻ろう
腹痛は
Let's get back!
What about your stomach?
It's fine!
どか行た
はあ
Huh?
≪くそちゃんとうめぇ≫
Damn. They're really good.
あいつセタだたんだ
So he's their setter.
コト上の王様て言われてた
影山飛雄てあいつだよな
That's Kageyama Tobio, the guy they call the King of the Court, right?
でセタてなんだけ
So, what's a setter again?
(泉)トスを上げる
ポジションだてば
I told you, that's the position that sets the ball!
Setter
昨日勉強したじゃん
(関向)そうだけ
We learned that yesterday!
We did?
(金田一)う
タイミング遅ぇよ
Your timing is too slow!
クイクはもと
速く入てこいつてんだろ
Like I keep telling you, quick attacks have to get in faster than that!
Sorry.
(金田一)悪い
(監督)影山
Kageyama,
速さにこだわりすぎるなよ
don't obsess over speed.
大事なのは
お前個人の技術じゃなく
Your personal technique isn't the most important thing.
スパイカに
いかに打たせるかだからな
It's how well you set up the ball for the spiker, got it?
分かてます
I know.
(応援団)わあ
It's finally, finally happening!
≪いよいよいよいよだ
(一同)お願いします
Let's have a good match!
(国見)
相手チムほんとちちぇ
The opposing team is really tiny.
コジ背番号背番号見せて
(関向)え
Kouji! Show them the number on your back!
Huh?
コジ
(関向)い
Kouji.
Sorry.
悪ぃ
ドンマイドンマイ
Don't sweat it.
Give us a nice serve!
ナイサ
(２人)あ
Kitagawa First                  Yukigaoka
おいおい１点も
入んねぇんじゃない
Hey, I don't think they're gonna get a single point.
いいじゃん早く終わて
はぁ
What's wrong with that? It'll end sooner.
I guess you're right.
そりゃそうだお
気にしない気にしない
Shake it off!
出していこう
(関向)おおう
Say something next time.
R-Right.
≪やとこの場所に立たんだ≫
I'm finally standing here.
≪簡単に終わらせてたまるか≫
I'm not gonna let it end that easily!
((え部員俺だけですか
What?
I'm the only club member?
((うん年々減てねぇ))
Yeah. The numbers have been dropping over the years.
((あそれと男子バレは
部活じゃなくて愛好会ね))
Oh, and boys' volleyball is more like a fanclub than an actual team.
((はあ
((どうするほかの部に替える
Oh.
What do you want to do? Join another club?
((それか女子に交ざる
((えそそれはちょと
Or do you wanna join the girls' team?
Uh, I'd rather not.
((一人でもやります
((そう
I'll do it alone!
Really?
I'll become the Little Giant!
((小さな巨人になります
((え何に
Huh? What?
ピ
(応援団)わあ
Kitagawa First
Yukigaoka
((う
((≫ナイサ
Nice serve.
Nice receive!
((≫ナイスレシブ
((≫ライト
Right!
((痛
Here!
≪ここ
((あぁ
((集合じゃあ走りに行くよ))
(一同)((はい
Gather 'round!
Okay, we're going running.
Right!
≪チャンス
Here's my chance!
Izumin! You're on a break, right?
((イズミン今休憩中だろ
トス上げてトス
I need you to set for me!
What? Set?
((はあトス
((スパイク打てみたいんだよ))
I wanna try spiking!
((無理無理
やたことないもん))
Forget it. I've never done it before.
((投げるので
投げるのでいいから
All I need you to do is throw it, okay?
((ダメだて先輩見てるし))
((≪集合
I can't! My upperclassmen are watching.
Gather 'round!
((おおす
((あ
C-Coming!
ピ
(応援団)わあ
Kitagawa First
Yukigaoka
(生徒)((なあ日向お前男なのに
女子バレ部なんだて
Hey, Hinata.
Why are you on the girls' volleyball team? You're a dude.
((ぶ
((マジかよお前))
Are you kidding me?
((ち違ぇよ))
(生徒)((誰が目当てなの
I-It isn't like that.
Which one are you after?
There are a couple of gorgeous third-years.
(生徒)
((３年に美人の先輩いたよな
((び美人の先輩はいるけど))
(生徒)((ほらいた
There are, but...
See? Told ya!
((違うてば
俺は男子バレ部
You're wrong! I'm on the boys' volleyball team!
(応援団)わあ
Certain
Victory
Kitagawa First Junior High School
(関向)((お前さぁ
You know, you sure do practice a lot for someone who never gets to play.
試合に出らんないのに
よく練習やれるよな))
((し試合には出るよ
そのうち))
I-I will play! Eventually!
((人集めてさ今んとこ
フラレぱなしだけど今に必ず))
I'll get lots of guys together.
Everyone turns me down, but you'll see!
(関向)((ふん))
((コジどう
What do you say, Kouji?
(関向)
((俺は何回フレばいいんだ
How many times do I have to turn you down?
(関向)く
ピ
((あイズミン
Hey, Izumin!
I just need you for a minute.
((ちょとでいいから
((ごめん今日塾なんだ))
Sorry, I have cram school today!
Kitagawa First                  Yukigaoka
(応援団)わあ
(泉)ごごめん
I-I'm sorry.
ドンマイドンマイ
(金田一)ラキラキ
Don't sweat it!
That was lucky!
(関向)((危ねぇ
((んうぐわ
Look out!
((翔陽大丈夫か
((痛ぇ
Shouyou, are you okay?
Ow...
((悪い))
Sorry.
((じゃあトス上げてよ
Okay, set for me!
≪今度こそ
I'll get it this time!
コジイズミン
Kouji! Izumin!
(泉)((ねえまだやんの
Hey, do I have to keep doing this?
((腕痛いし
ボル思た所に飛ばないし
My arms hurt, and the ball never goes where I want it to.
もうやだよ))
((お願いもう一本だけ))
I'm tired of this.
Please, just one more!
((１年生たちも
入てきてくれるし))
Some first-years will join me, you'll see!
You said just one more a few minutes ago.
((さきも
もう一本だけて言たよ))
((ほんとに最後だからね))
((あざす
This really is the last one!
Thanks!
((いくよ))
Here comes.
Oops, sorry!
((あごめんえ
行け翔ちゃん
Go for it, Shou!
≪俺は確かにチビだけど
この脚で飛び越えてみせる≫
I know I'm short,
but I'll make my legs jump higher
≪どんな壁も
than any wall!
(金田一)よしゃ
翔ちゃんドンマイ
Yes!
Shake it off, Shou!
(関向)次も上げてやるからな
ごごめん
I'll get the next one to you too!
I'm sorry I wasted such a good set.
せかく上がたのに
次は決めるから
I'll make the next one count.
Haikyuu !!
(金田一)おしゃ
Right on!
Yukigaoka                  Kitagawa First
うわあの５番も強烈だな
Yikes, their number five is intense.
でもまあ２セト目は
そこそこ点取れてるじゃん
At least Yukigaoka is starting to score a few points in the second set.
雪ヶ丘
全部相手のミスだけどな
Those are all from their opponent's errors.
(関向)上がた
(２人)あ
It's up!
Shou.
翔ちゃん
く
The wall!
≪壁
向こう側が全然見えない≫
I can't see the other side whatsoever.
ああ
完全に読まれちゃてるよ
They're anticipating every move.
And the guy can really jump.
すげぇジャンプ力なのに
Shouyou, go for another shot!
It's such a waste.
もたいないよな
(泉)翔ちゃんドンマイ
Shou, shake it off!
(金田一)う
ピ
(金田一)あぶね
もと速く
That was close!
Go faster!
ち
(国見)ナイス
Nice.
今日も相変わらず
ムチャぶりトスだな
He's doing his crazy sets again.
The opponent's defense is practically nonexistent,
相手のブロク
いないも同然なのに
so why is he taking it so seriously?
何マジになてんだよ
じゃあお前らが本気でやるのは
一体いつだよ
Then when are all of you planning to take this seriously?!
Stop that! We're in the middle of a match!
よせ試合中だぞ
怖ぇ
Yikes.
Yukigaoka                  Kitagawa First
北一のセタてさ
うまいんだけどなんか
Kita First's setter is really good at what he does,
but it's almost like he's playing volleyball by himself.
独りでバレやてるみたいだ
ピ
(川島)オライあ
おしまたサビスエス
I've got it!
Okay, here comes another service ace!
まだだ
(金田一)あれは無理だろ
Not yet!
He'll never get that.
≪まだ落ちてないまだ
It hasn't fallen yet.
It's not over!
ピ
あうう
(泉)翔ちゃん
Shou?
Wow, that looks painful.
(金田一)うわ痛そう
(国見)頑張るねぇ
He's a fighter.
Yukigaoka                  Kitagawa First
あと１点で終わりだな雪ヶ丘
うん
One more point will finish off Yukigaoka.
Yeah.
Dammit!
(川島)あのすみません僕
Listen, I'm sorry. I didn't...
ごめん次は取る
(川島)あの
Sorry. I'll get the next one!
Listen!
ケケガとかしちゃても
あれだし
It would be bad if you were to get hurt,
and we're never gonna beat these guys,
正直勝てる相手じゃないし
One more of those.
so why are you trying so hard?
なんでそこまで
え
Huh?
えとええ
Uh, what?
I don't really understand the question, but...
よく分かんないけどでも
まだ負けてないよ
we haven't lost yet.
That's right. It's simple.
≪そうだ単純なことだ≫
No matter how tricky it is to retrieve the ball, there's only one reason to go after it.
≪どんな難しいボルだろうが
追う理由は一つ≫
くコジ
Kouji.
It hasn't hit the ground yet.
≪まだコトに
ボルは落ちていないから≫
Shou.
No matter what the disadvantage,
there's one reason to keep fighting.
≪どんな劣勢だろうが
戦い続ける理由は一つ≫
We haven't lost yet.
(２人)
≪まだ負けていないから
ワンタチ
触たカバだ
I touched it!
He made contact! Cover it!
≪こりゃ取れないよ≫
I'll never get this.
ピ
おしゃ
All right!
Yukigaoka                  Kitagawa First
(２人)ははあ
最後まで追えよ
Don't stop chasing it halfway!
わ悪い
M-My bad.
Don't let your guard down until the match is over!
勝負がついてねぇのに
気ぃ抜いてんじゃねぇよ
分かてるけどさこの点差が
ひくり返るような奇跡は
I'm aware of that,
but it would take a miracle for them to overtake us now.
今の１点は奇跡じゃない
取られたんだ
The point they just got on us was no miracle. It was stolen.
あいつに点を取られたんだよ
Our point was stolen by him!
(国見)いや
まあそりゃそうなんだけどさ
Uh, well. Yeah, I guess, but...
((諦めさえしなきゃ
As long as we don't give up!
≫ネトイン落ちるぞ前前
It's over the net!
It's falling! Move up!
I'm open, Izumi!
(森)オライ泉さん
(泉)よしゃ翔ちゃん頼んだ
All right! Shou, get it!
≪トスミス
ドリブルは取られてない≫
He messed up the set?
There was no double hit.
≪でもそちには誰も
But nobody's over there.
≪今レフトにいたはずなのに
I'm positive he went left.
≪マクしてたはずなのに
I'm positive I had him marked!
≪なんで
How?
≪なんでそこにいる
How can he be there?!
Oh no! Shou!
(泉)うわ翔ちゃん
君大丈夫
Are you okay?
アアウト
O-Out of bounds?
Yukigaoka                  Kitagawa First
(応援団)わあ
(泉)翔ちゃんケガしてない
Shou, are you hurt?
≪目で追うだけで精一杯だた≫
I could barely follow him with my eyes.
≪今のは完全にセタのミス≫
That was 100% the setter's fault.
It isn't as though he anticipated the set going backward,
≪バクトスなんか
予測してたわけがない≫
≪にもかかわらず打てたのか
but he hit it anyway?
≪あいつは
あのトスに反応できるのか
Can he react to sets like that?
(泉)翔ちゃん整列
Shou, get in line.
≪高い運動能力反射≫
(金田一)おい影山
High athletic ability. Reflexes.
Hey, Kageyama. What're you doing?
何やてんだ
≪自分の体を操るセンス≫
The skills necessary to exercise body control.
Get in line!
And finally, tenacity for victory.
≪そして勝利への執着≫
For everything he does have...
≪それらを持ていながら
お前は３年間何やてたんだ
What have you been doing for the last three years?!
Excuse me?!
なんだと
やめとけて
Just don't!
You don't know anything about what he did for these last three years!
(関向)お前はこいつの３年間を
何も知らないくせに
(泉)今それをここで言ても
しょうがないだろ
This isn't the time or place for this!
I can't help it.
＜中学最初で最後の公式戦＞
My first and last official match in junior high.
All of you, get in line!
Shou, c'mon. Let's line up.
(泉)翔ちゃん並ぼう
Yukigaoka                  Kitagawa First
＜獲得セト数０＞
Sets won: zero.
＜総試合時間僅か３１分＞
Elapsed match time: a mere thirty-one minutes.
The King of the Court, huh?
Karasuno High
Volleyball Team
(菅原)コト上の王様か
He'll be a tough opponent once he gets to high school.
(澤村)高校に上がてきたら
厄介な敵になりそうだな
Karasuno High
Volleyball Team
(田中)あのチビも楽しみすね
Karasuno High
Volleyball Team
The short kid is promising too.
Karasuno High
Volleyball Team
(２人)ふぅ
しょうがないて
What could we do?
相手全国候補だたらしいじゃん
あ
I heard they're contenders for winning nationals.
(金田一)ああ腹減た
Wow, I'm starving.
(国見)お前はそればかだな
That's all you ever think about.
相手が強くても弱くても
No matter how strong or weak your opponent is,
結果は
勝つか負けるかのどちかで
it all comes down to winning or losing.
負けたら
もうコトには立てない
Once you lose, you have to leave the court.
(泉)あ翔ちゃん
(関向)翔陽
Shou?
Shouyou?
お前が
Hey!
コトに君臨する王様なら
If you're supposed to be the king who rules the court,
そいつを倒して
I'm going to defeat you
俺がいちばん長く
コトに立てやる
and stay on the court the longest!
コトに残るのは勝たヤツ
Only the winner gets to stay on the court.
Only the strong.
強いヤツだけだ
勝ち残りたかたら
強くなてみろよ
If you want to stay in the tournament, get better at it.
≪俺に足りないもの≫
What am I lacking?
(２人)あ
今日はありがとう
Thanks for your help today!
ババカ野郎
Y-You idiot!
You don't have to thank us!
お礼なんかしなくていいんだよ
うう
Huh? Why are you crying, Kouji?
あれ
なんでコジも泣いてるの
I-I'm not crying!
(関向)な泣いてねぇよ
Kitagawa First
Loses Just Barely
(関向)じゃあな翔陽
(泉)元気でね翔ちゃん
Bye, Shouyou!
Take care, Shou!
＜チャリンコで
ひと山越えて３０分＞
Thirty minutes by bicycle over some hills!
＜今日から
宮城県立烏野高等学校＞
Today's my first day at Miyagi Prefectural Karasuno High School!
サカ部入りませんか
Wanna join the soccer team?
野球部で
マネジメントされてみない
Wanna try managing the baseball team?
(清水)これ今んとこの入部届
(澤村)サンキュ少ないな
These are our current applicants.
Thanks.
We didn't get that many.
昔は多かたはずなのに
(菅原)こから増えるて大地
I know we used to get more.
We'll get more soon, Daichi.
Kiyoko, you look lovely today!
(田中)
潔子さん今日も美しいす
ガン無視興奮するす
I love it when she ignores me!
≪来た来た烏野
I'm here! I'm here, at Karasuno!
≪これからいぱい練習して
I'm gonna practice tons...
≪そんであの王様に
and then challenge that king...
リベンジだ
...to a revenge match!
ななんでいる
う
Wh-Why are you here?!
ガン
痛
Ow.
Next Episode Preview
What is the King of the Court doing here?
Is it someone else?
A lookalike?
なんでいんだよコト上の王様
人違い他人の空似
Someone who just happens to look like him,
who just happens to be in the gym,
who just happens to be trying to serve?
たまたまあいつに似てるヤツが
たまたま体育館で
Get real!
たまたま
サブを打とうとしてただけ
Next time on Haikyuu!!:
Episode Two:
Karasuno High School Volleyball Team
"Karasuno High School Volleyball Team."
なわけないじゃん